<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-20T12:56:08-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/</id><title type="html">The Wrap</title><subtitle>Tips and Tricks for Gifting and Surviving</subtitle><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">No Waste Wrapping</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/no-waste-wrapping/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No Waste Wrapping" /><published>2018-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/no-waste-wrapping</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/no-waste-wrapping/">&lt;p&gt;Wrapping paper can really make the gift sparkle and stand out. There are so many choices in the stores, and you can even custom order your own. Paper for any occasion or preference is out there for us. We (all of people) seem to like it. And why not, it sure is pretty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to research from Hallmark, Americans spend approximately $3.2 billion a year on wrapping paper and bags.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps because it is so pretty, we use a lot of wrapping paper - and what do we do with it? For the most part, we throw it in the trash. Anyone else save wrapping paper and tissue and bags and all of that? My hand is up, but the stash does not always fit what you need to wrap. And that is when we need to reach for a roll or flat of wrapping paper, a bag, or find an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or, I guess we can just give the gift unwrapped?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, no. The thing is, we don’t just want to hand over a thing. Presentation is part of it. There is a thrill that goes along with the uncertainty - the not knowing - the mystery that is in the wrap. &lt;strong&gt;Right?!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-can-i-use-instead-of-gift-wrap-and-bags-to-present-gifts&quot;&gt;“What can I use instead of gift wrap and bags to present gifts?”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we go: 8 alternatives that are awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-newspaper&quot;&gt;1. Newspaper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Newspaper is perfect for wrapping. It looks good in large and small packages, and the words do not matter. The comics, games, and weather sections offer color and variety. We love how easy it is to work with newspaper. Newspaper is also a useful stuffing material for other wrapping methods - both shredded and balled. Note: you may be able to get blank newspaper ends from a local paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-paper-bags&quot;&gt;2. Paper bags&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paper bags are slightly less easy than newspaper and may be more readily available - depending on your reading and shopping habits! Cut or pull the seams to get a flat piece of bag for wrapping or use the bag as is and stuff with a soft material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-fabric-shopping-bags&quot;&gt;3. Fabric shopping bags&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I somehow end up with more of these reusable bags than I need - all the time. Grocery chains give them out, they come with your race packets, and they are very affordable should you want to buy them. We like to give them as is and stuff, so the giftee can use the bag if they like, but I’ve also seen the bags cut and folded as wrapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-food-storage-containers&quot;&gt;4. Food storage containers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of wrapping with something that can be reused, why not use some plastic or glass storage containers. Storage containers are useful and solid enough for gifting. You can find them pre-printed in many designs, or use the plain ones and line the inside with butcher or parchment paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-maps&quot;&gt;5. Maps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember maps? Like, actual real paper maps you could trace your finger on? They are out there, collecting dust, in houses everywhere. Be brave, rip or cut maps out of old atlases and travel books or unfold those complex puzzles. The colors and designs are mesmerizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;6-your-drawingsor-your-kids-drawings&quot;&gt;6. Your drawings…or your kid’s drawings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone with kids knows that they will make at home and also bring home ample artwork. It does not all fit on the fridge, and most of it is not museum quality. Fun art is perfect for wrapping, though. If you don’t have kiddos or you just want to take a go of it yourself, you can draw on butcher paper, drawing paper, or just about any paper that you have around. Not just drawing but also stamping or painting will work to bring a little spark and interest to the gift. Two notes of caution: &lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt; construction paper is too inflexible to make a good wrapping material for most items - you can make it work if you are very gentle and &lt;em&gt;2&lt;/em&gt; plain white printer paper is generally see through - try a heavier paper or multiple layers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;7-mugs-or-mason-jars&quot;&gt;7. Mugs or mason jars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small items fit so nicely inside of mugs. You can purchase mugs at just about any home goods or thrift store, get custom mugs from a local maker, paint to personalize yourself at a pottery shop, … or make them yourself if you have that kind of skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;8-clothing&quot;&gt;8. Clothing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are gifting clothing, you can use it, inside out, to wrap itself or an accompanying gift. This works best with sturdy items that are unlikely to rip or stain, like colored T-shirts - which happen to be very popular gifts. You can use scrap fabric in a similar way - fleece is great for wrapping!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not opposed to wrapping paper - it is beautiful and flexible and well suited to its purpose. You can do what works best for your gift.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let us know if you have another great wrapping alternative!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Williams, Geoff. 2014. The Hidden Costs of the Holidays. U.S.News. Money. November 28. Retrieved from: https://money.usnews.com/money/personal-finance/articles/2014/11/28/the-hidden-costs-of-the-holidays &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">What can I use instead of gift wrap and bags to present gifts?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Fun Back to School Gifts</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-back-to-school-gifts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Fun Back to School Gifts" /><published>2018-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-back-to-school-gifts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-back-to-school-gifts/">&lt;p&gt;Even if you are not in school, the back-to-school vibe gets you. Parents, kids, and teachers are all in the thick of it. They are out buying boring things from lists, things they need, sometimes things that they don’t even want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-short-back-to-school-gift-idea-list&quot;&gt;Our short back to school gift idea list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can make the whole thing just a little tiny bit better with the simplest of things. Here are five fun ideas to bring joy back to school for kids and teachers (and maybe other peoples).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-silly-erasers&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Silly erasers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hands down, the biggest hit with all ages is erasers. Don’t go crazy - no one can use 300 erasers. A couple of well chosen ones may seem like an insignificant thing in the moment, but will be used and enjoyed many, many times. There are eraser sets for just about any taste out there, but you can’t go wrong with cute animals or puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-smelly-anything&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Smelly anything&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you remember scratch and sniff stickers? They are still cool. Kids and grownups love them so. There are now also smelly pencils and markers. The markers are easiest to find but likely get the least amount of use - we just don’t have occasion to marker all the time. A fun smelling pencil can be a joy to a kid - or coffee scented for the teachers. It’s all in good fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-not-your-average-notebooks&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Not your average notebooks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope. Not the plain ones. A nice weird notebook. One with brightly colored paper, dotted, or even blank sheets. A notebook with a lock or a super fun feely cover. These are the notebooks that become journals, artbooks, screenplays, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-key-chains&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Key chains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key chains are fun for keys, sure, but they are also fun for bag decorations. Help your favorite soon to be in school someone with a bag bauble. Personality matches are certainly a plus here. Personally, I have a guitar playing horseradish, and it makes me super happy, but that isn’t for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-washi-tape&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Washi tape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit more trendy than our typical gift advice, washi tape is small designer masking type tape that is perfect for adding flair to notes, journals, and decorating things. “Washi” means “Japanese paper” but the tapes, even from Japan, are masking tape - the most popular brand is MT, but there are so many different styles and colors. Even a plain roll can be put to good use in personalizing a binder or book cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you get all As!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">Even if you are not in school, the back-to-school vibe gets you. Parents, kids, and teachers are all in the thick of it. They are out buying boring things from lists, things they need, sometimes things that they don’t even want.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Free Wallpapers from Gifts Done</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/5freewallpaper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Free Wallpapers from Gifts Done" /><published>2018-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/5freewallpaper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/5freewallpaper/">&lt;p&gt;Who’s awesome? You’re awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Gifts Done, we constantly get to see amazing small business makers coming up with just the right gifts and our users celebrating with their friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love all of you. We made a few free wallpapers that you can download to decorate your computer desktop. We hope they make you feel amazing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gifts-done.com/wallpaper&quot;&gt;Pick your free wallpaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are not really artists, we are open to suggestions - what kind of wallpapers do you want to see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep it up. -Jen and Jess&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="perks" /><summary type="html">Who’s awesome? You’re awesome.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Fun Summer Gifts</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-summer-gifts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Fun Summer Gifts" /><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-summer-gifts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-summer-gifts/">&lt;p&gt;We love summer. Do you love summer? We’ve been chatting up our friends and scrolling through Instagram, of course, to find a few fun summer gifts. Give them to yourself or someone else for whatever occasion inspires you this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-short-summer-gift-idea-list&quot;&gt;Our short summer gift idea list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t even have to buy all of this cool stuff. We don’t link to shops or specific items because we think you can handle that part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-homemade-popsicles&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Homemade popsicles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously - the probability that someone will turn down a homemade popsicle is approximately &amp;lt; 1%. That’s a totally scientific number that we made up, but we are pretty sure it is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make popsicles your own by following one of these three approaches to make the stuff to pour into your popsicle molds, or Dixie cups if you are really fancy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend milk and fruit - we use coconut milk and/or heavy cream to get extra fun creaminess&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make pudding - people love pudding pops - by people, we mostly mean kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go with straight juice - these are super sweet - we cut ours with water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-shell-or-rock-art&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Shell or rock art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom make a thing with some items you collect while out exploring (note, the real gift here is that you get to go exploring to get the things! - we are so sneaky).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect small shells or rocks at the beach - not if you are in a leave no trace kinda place - and glue or paint them to make a friend’s name or a frame for a picture of you together. It will hold up for years as a memory of your experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-yard-games&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Yard games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are partial to cornhole and horseshoes because they don’t take a great amount of effort and are portable. Go ahead and gift yourself a yard game and then invite everyone over to play…again and again. It is joy on repeat to gather friends and family together. Serve up some of those popsicles!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-custom-insulated-drinkware&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Custom insulated drinkware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know how you want your iced drinks, well, iced? Your friends and family do, too! You can be the person who sets everyone up with insulated drinkware with a favorite saying, joke, image, or just a name. We know there are so many makers who do this sort of thing; you can probably find one in your neighborhood. Celebrate the gift of cold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-waterproof-fold-or-roll-up-mats&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Waterproof fold or roll up mats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be ready for an impromptu picnic, time at the beach, or a nap in the woods with a mat that will shield you from damp ground, bugs, and/or spiky plant parts. These mats roll or fold up, so you can just keep one in your car or go bag and bust it out in a time of need. Any time can be outside time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you have a splendid summer!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">We love summer. Do you love summer? We’ve been chatting up our friends and scrolling through Instagram, of course, to find a few fun summer gifts. Give them to yourself or someone else for whatever occasion inspires you this summer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">July Instagram Challenge</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/july-ig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="July Instagram Challenge" /><published>2018-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/july-ig</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/july-ig/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Summer is a state of mind”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our heart and soul is in our wonderful suppliers, and we want everyone to have a little fun this summer. To that end, we are continuing our instagram challenge for suppliers, and anyone can join the fun. Let’s see what direction your month takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;July Gifts Done Instagram Challenge&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.gifts-done.com/assets/images/ig_challenge_july.png&quot; alt=&quot;gifts done instagram challenge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-the-most-of-it&quot;&gt;Make the Most of It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become part of the party by posting something related to the challenge each day. Be sure to also use and follow the main challenge hashtag &lt;strong&gt;#gdempowers&lt;/strong&gt; - this is how everyone can see your posts and we can repost you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is so exciting to see how other people use a prompt. Be wild, be wacky, just be yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate other makers and creators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet new people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-repost-you&quot;&gt;We’ll Repost You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love seeing what our suppliers (and future suppliers) are up to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="social" /><category term="suppliers" /><summary type="html">“Summer is a state of mind”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">22 Self Care Ideas</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/22selfcare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="22 Self Care Ideas" /><published>2018-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/22selfcare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/22selfcare/">&lt;p&gt;How are you feeling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel tense, overwhelmed, nervous, or uncomfortable, it may be time to take a self-care break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we love you, we spent a few minutes coming up with a list of 22 ideas for self care. You can try these as written or build on them to come up with something that is just right for you. Don’t let our ideas hold back your creativity and expression!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Peaceful rock stacking&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.gifts-done.com/assets/images/jeremy-thomas-75753-unsplash&quot; alt=&quot;stacked pebbles Photo by Jeremy Thomas on Unsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sit in the sunshine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get out pencil and paper and draw a baby elephant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dig a hole&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a spaceship out of toy bricks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find some crayons and melt them together to make a giant crayon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solve a rubix cube (&lt;em&gt;working: not if this will make you angry&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draw your name in bubble letters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get dressed up in a way that makes you feel fabulous and get a friend to take your picture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read a YA novel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put your headphones in, put your current favorite song on repeat and sing along&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List out all of the things that you are thinking about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clip your nails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take your dog, or a shelter dog, for a walk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover your whole body with moisturizer after bathing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to the beach or woods, try to find two things that are the same&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a blanket fort, take a snack, flashlight, and magazine inside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plant something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do a jigsaw puzzle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blow bubbles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a kids coloring book - color an easy picture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Splash in the rain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draw a maze and then solve it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little tip - research shows that little doses of self care are critical to mental health and wellness. Constantly feeding ourselves with treats and rewards can be hazardous to that same mental health. Please self-care responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="selfcare" /><summary type="html">How are you feeling?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Healthy Summer Snacks</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/healthy-summer-snacks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Healthy Summer Snacks" /><published>2018-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/healthy-summer-snacks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/healthy-summer-snacks/">&lt;p&gt;Summer food can be the tastiest - barbecues, ice cream, sno cones, fair food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But our tasty treats usually take hours to prepare and are not all that healthy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the conundrum with summer. We want to be healthy and have the energy to spend all day outside, and we also want to enjoy tasty stuff. Our sugar loving brains may be crying out for a trip to the ice cream parlor, but our wallets and future selves want us to make other choices. While we are no experts on food here, we have spent years with this very same problem. Over the years, we’ve been able to come up with some tricks for healthy summer snacks that keep us (and our families) going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prepare-ahead&quot;&gt;Prepare ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often want to run out of the house for a day at the lake, beach, mountain, and it would never happen if we needed to stop along the way to pick up snacks. Mostly because we would faff the day away planning out when and where we would eat next. As time has passed, we’ve found some tried and true snacks that we just keep on hand ready to go out with whoever is going. Most of these are not seasonal (because fresh fruit and what not is all at risk of being smooshed). The gist is buying in bulk stuff that you will eat and then splitting it up into single servings immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;trail-mix&quot;&gt;Trail mix&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granola, hippie food, whatever. A mix of nuts or nuts and fruit or nuts and chocolate can really make the day go by easier. Not only does it keep well, but it is light and does not require sitting down in a dry place. The varieties of mixes that you can put together are endless. Ours goes really fast when we make a special batch of honey or cinnamon nuts in the mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jerky-or-dried-meats&quot;&gt;Jerky or dried meats&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dried foods last forever (or at least seem to) if you can avoid noshing them up. Dried meats especially can pack a protein filled punch for the adventurous. There are so many premade varieties in the store, but most of those are so expensive and so limited in flavor - admittedly, this seems to be getting better. You can make jerky in a warm oven with thinly sliced meats - marinate in your favorite flavors to shake things up. We like to go with combinations of spicy and peppery, and every once in awhile, sweet barbecue - surprisingly good on turkey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;salad-it-up&quot;&gt;Salad it up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joking aside, summer is a great time for salad. The greens just keep growing, and you can get lettuces and cabbages for cheap (or for the effort of growing them). We so, so, so recommend keeping some meats leftover from barbecues to use in salad in the coming week. This works, we promise - even teenage boys* are happy to eat steak salad. (&lt;em&gt;and aren’t they a hard to please bunch&lt;/em&gt;) The trick we use here is to not have the same salad every time. So, one day, we have egg salad with ripe grape tomatoes, and we won’t serve that one again for awhile - taco salad (with no silly shell) anyone? It’s as simple as trading out traditional dressing for salsa and ensuring you have limes and avocado on hand. Here are 13 salads for the 13 weeks of summer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;egg salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;steak salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;taco salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cobb salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;strawberry salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beet salad (check out how the New Zealanders do this)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;coleslaw&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;teriyaki chicken salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;caesar salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;corn salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;melon salad&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;potato salad (&lt;em&gt;you knew we would sneak that in&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;barbecue chicken salad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cook-in-batches&quot;&gt;Cook in batches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one wants to heat up the house in the summer. That’s why we are out grilling and busy noshing on salad, right? But some things we do want to cook, and we might want to do it in the house. We try batch cooking items that keep pretty well, so that we can get by with the least amount of artificial house heating as possible. You may have different things that you use a lot, but we go through so many eggs, chicken, and potatoes (pretty much every kind) that these get special treatment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;eggs&quot;&gt;Eggs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We boil eggs by the dozen, often two dozen, and keep them in the fridge for eating as is - what is simpler than a boiled egg? or turning into deviled eggs or egg salad in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;chicken&quot;&gt;Chicken&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We bake and saute chicken in several pound batches to have different flavors on hand for sandwiches and salads. It is so much easier to just do it all at once than to cook chicken a couple of times per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;potatoes&quot;&gt;Potatoes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We boil and bake potatoes in bunches - as much as we can fit - and then save the rest in the fridge and freezer. Potatoes keep very well, but we never really have to test it because they are so easy to eat hot or cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-crazy-with-the-berries&quot;&gt;Get crazy with the berries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berries are sweet and, freshly picked, embody summer’s promises. Early in the season, strawberries lead the way - flushing markets with their bright red skin. Cherries and blueberries follow with their deeper rich flavors. Then we get boysenberries, raspberries, blackberries, and more to take us through fall. The great thing about these berries is that they are tastiest right away, but somehow we can only eat so many. Go ahead, try to gorge yourself on berries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We like to pick berries and sometimes do the all you can eat while you are at the farm kinda thing. We also like the much easier option of picking up a pint or two at the market and using them right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-delicious-things-to-do-with-berries&quot;&gt;Three delicious things to do with berries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend the first one the most because it is the least amount of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eat them as is&lt;/strong&gt;, as snacks in themselves, with granola/cereal, or on top of salads or yogurt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mix them into stuff&lt;/strong&gt;. Not even kidding. Have you ever spread raspberry butter on a piece of toast - it’s amazing and just requires smooshing some raspberries into some softened butter. Also, the obvious - smoothies and milkshakes are better with berries. A few recipes:
  &lt;em&gt;Strawberry Banana&lt;/em&gt; 1 pint strawberries, 1 banana (preferably frozen), 2 cups milk (any kind)
  &lt;em&gt;Cherry Coconut&lt;/em&gt; 2 pints cherries, 1 can coconut milk (with cream)
  &lt;em&gt;Cloud Berry&lt;/em&gt; 3 pints berries (any kind), 1 cup iced cream, 1 cup whipping cream (or coconut cream)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can them&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes, you knew we were going to suggest canning. You can make jam or jellies, or can them with framboise for an ice cream topper like no other. Who says you have to save your canned goods. Enjoy them now. Now!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s wishing you a delicious summer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="food" /><summary type="html">We all eat, but somehow eating easy is still hard</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">June Instagram Challenge</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/june-ig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="June Instagram Challenge" /><published>2018-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/june-ig</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/june-ig/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life is short - smile while you still have teeth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our heart and soul is in our wonderful suppliers, and we want everyone to have a little fun. To that end, we created an instagram challenge for suppliers, but anyone can join the fun. Let’s see what direction your month takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;June Gifts Done Instagram Challenge&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.gifts-done.com/assets/images/ig_challenge_june.png&quot; alt=&quot;gifts done instagram challenge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-the-most-of-it&quot;&gt;Make the Most of It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become part of the party by posting something related to the challenge each day. Be sure to also use and follow the main challenge hashtag &lt;strong&gt;#gdempowers&lt;/strong&gt; - this is how everyone can see your posts and we can repost you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is so exciting to see how other people use a prompt. Be wild, be wacky, just be yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate other makers and creators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet new people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-repost-you&quot;&gt;We’ll Repost You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love seeing what our suppliers (and future suppliers) are up to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="social" /><category term="suppliers" /><summary type="html">“Life is short - smile while you still have teeth.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Expanding Birthday Greetings</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/notebirthday/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Expanding Birthday Greetings" /><published>2018-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/notebirthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/notebirthday/">&lt;p&gt;What do I say?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a little unsure of how to approach writing a personal note. You are not alone. One of the most common questions that we get is around what to say. Here, we give you a few tips for expanding what you write. We also provide a list of simple phrases that you can use if all else fails: &lt;a href=&quot;/20-canned-birthday/&quot;&gt;20 canned Birthday Greetings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make their birthday special-er.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-tips-for-expanding-your-own-birthday-greeting&quot;&gt;5 Tips for expanding your own birthday greeting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Include a memory from the year.&lt;/strong&gt; One of the nicest things about reading someone else’s reflection is that it lets us relive a moment. Even if the memory seems paltry, share it. You can say something like, “I am so happy that I got to see you in March for coffee - can you believe it has already been so long!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a fun nickname.&lt;/strong&gt; If you usually call your friend “Nick” but sometimes, you call him “The Oranginator” because of that one time at the arcade, go ahead and bring that up. Address the note to the nickname. Caution - don’t do this if the nickname is not appreciated by your friend or loved one, or if they might not remember. People can be very confused or hurt by nicknames that are more like teasing than like good old fashioned fun.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Close with a promise.&lt;/strong&gt; Ending your note with a “Sincerely, Jo” is fine, but it can be even better to say, “Talk to you soon, Jo” This way, they not only have a great note, and likely a gift, from you, but they can also know that you are going to call or come over or plan some event.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wax poetic about their good qualities.&lt;/strong&gt; Flattery, when done well, really does lift the spirits. Take the time to include a few words or sentences about what you like and/or love about this person. Perhaps, “&lt;em&gt;I love that you always have a new joke to share - even the corny ones&lt;/em&gt;” or “&lt;em&gt;You always look so put together - I enjoy being jealous of your morning routine&lt;/em&gt;”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Share a historic fact from your relationship.&lt;/strong&gt; Relationship is used rather loosely here. Sometimes, we send gifts or cards to people who we are not particularly close to. How long have you guys known each other? How many coffees/movies/late working nights have you shared? How many times has he or she saved you when things were not going well? If you can’t think of any, you can share a historic fact about the year that they were born or month. “Did you know that Austin Powers shares your birthday?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take these ideas and run with them. People love to read just a little from you. Gifts Done will include your personalized note (however long) with your gifts. If for some reason, your note is too long to fit in our text box, you can email it to us, and we promise to take care of it for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can do this!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">What should I put on a birthday note besides here is a thing from me?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Apologize for a Missed Gift</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/apologize/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Apologize for a Missed Gift" /><published>2018-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/apologize</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/apologize/">&lt;p&gt;Many of our customers at Gifts Done are just like us (shocker) and have missed gifts in the past. In fact, most of the feedback that we get from users is how they love not doing that anymore because we take care of them. If you are not using an automated gifting service, it is possible, maybe, that you will miss an important day for someone. It feels terrible, right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1499171138085-a60c4e752ff7?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=a0423a28d0490b60b12192def27aa4c4&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1050&amp;amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;sadman&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mistakes happen - and it can make you feel terrible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are all different, of course, and you may have friends and family who don’t care about their birthdays and anniversaries and what not. However, when you do forget for someone who is close to you, there can be hurt feelings. Both for them and you. There’s no need to beat yourself up about it - you can simply not go back into the past and change your actions. You can take control and recover. Here’s our 3 step plan - don’t be shocked at how simple it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-acknowledge-that-you-made-a-mistake&quot;&gt;1. Acknowledge that you made a mistake&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more for you than anyone else. Start here. If you are not ready to talk to the person who you have hurt, start with you. “I have made a mistake”. Then, you start to own the process of recovery and you can address what has happened. Mistakes happen, so this step puts the missed gift into a category of things we know how to handle. At this point, you don’t want to make any promises to yourself or anyone else. You want to figure out the root cause. Here are possible mistakes that some people make that cause them to miss important days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You did not know when or what the event was&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You did not know that the person cared so much&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You were aware of the upcoming event but you did not make a plan to do anything about it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You were aware of the upcoming event and you made a plan but you did not stick with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are possible - there may even be more. The point here is just to find out where the gap is that let you make a mistake. You can be really specific if you want or just think about it in general terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-determine-a-strategy-for-not-repeating-the-mistake&quot;&gt;2. Determine a strategy for not repeating the mistake&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Once you know why you missed this special day, it is much easier to figure out how to do something about it.&lt;/em&gt; Not all causes can have a clear plan of action, though. If you just didn’t know, it is fine, but not really actionable, to say, “I won’t let this happen again because I will pay more attention/ask more/know more in the future” Frankly, we just don’t know what we don’t know, and there is nothing that can be done about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our experience - most missed gifts are caused by people just not being able to get to gifts because there are so many other competing priorities - people are trying to give 100% of themselves to work, family, hobbies, etc. When you have so many truly important things to do, it can be hard to remember much less prioritize shopping or sometimes even just saying “I am so happy for you on this day” - because the actual day slips our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your strategies may vary, but here are a few that we’ve used or heard others using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly planning&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain a habit of actively searching for, listing, and taking action on important events every month - one of our users even suggested putting sticky notes by the door with each date - so you may have one that says “May 20 - Sally’s 40th birthday” that you stick up there on May 1 and have to walk past and look at every day. It sounds kind of genius, really.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set up a reminder service&lt;/strong&gt; There are plenty of reminder services where you can enter dates and get a phone call or text message to do something. One way to customize your reminders is through the If This Than That application - so you can get just the right kind of notification for you - you can even connect the reminder to your smart lights now, so maybe you want the lights to be purple when there is something you need to do. We don’t know what will work best for your situation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a service like Gifts Done&lt;/strong&gt; Obviously, we are a little biased here. Setting up all of your gift events with your own budget and notes just when it works for you, is the easiest way. You can even get an annual membership so that you can save money when you send more than 10 gifts per year. It is easy and you know that your gifts will come from and benefit small businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask people to remind you&lt;/strong&gt; It seems a little weird, but you can ask people to let you know when things that are important to them are coming up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1484973768669-7fb6b5451095?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=b5cc69681633be6abd6a87cd8d3b350e&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1049&amp;amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;women on couch head down&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;A genuine apology is tough but oh so quick&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-genuinely-apologize&quot;&gt;3. Genuinely apologize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are empowered with understanding how you made a mistake and what you can do about it to avoid it next time - now it is time to apologize. We recommend doing this in person (if possible) and one on one. Apologies can feel hard at first, and you may be nervous. You can psych yourself up by thinking about how you feel when someone apologizes to you. You probably don’t bite, and they probably won’t either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always start with a simple, “I’m sorry” and never use the word “but”.&lt;/em&gt; Apologies are almost always of the formula: simple sorry + what I did + how I will do better next time. They do not include excuses or turn the attention back on the apologizer. This is important. If you made a mistake, even if the other person made one too, you can only own your own mistake. If Sally never told me that her birthday is May 20, and I miss it - well, I did not know that it was her birthday and the root cause of that could be that she did not tell me. I can still make her feel better by saying something like, “I am sorry that I missed your birthday. I did not know it was your birthday, and I have it in my calendar now, so we can celebrate next year!”. Now, everyone feels better. If Sally chooses to apologize to me for unreasonable expectations - that is a completely different matter than I have no control over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s wishing you never need apologize.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">I did not send my friend a gift when she expected one, what do I do?</summary></entry></feed>