<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-02T13:25:11-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/</id><title type="html">The Wrap</title><subtitle>Tips and Tricks for Gifting and Surviving</subtitle><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">5 Free Wallpapers from Gifts Done</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/5freewallpaper/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Free Wallpapers from Gifts Done" /><published>2018-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/5freewallpaper</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/5freewallpaper/">&lt;p&gt;Who’s awesome? You’re awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here at Gifts Done, we constantly get to see amazing small business makers coming up with just the right gifts and our users celebrating with their friends and family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love all of you. We made a few free wallpapers that you can download to decorate your computer desktop. We hope they make you feel amazing. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gifts-done.com/wallpaper&quot;&gt;Pick your free wallpaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are not really artists, we are open to suggestions - what kind of wallpapers do you want to see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keep it up. -Jen and Jess&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">Who’s awesome? You’re awesome.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Fun Summer Gifts</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-summer-gifts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Fun Summer Gifts" /><published>2018-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-summer-gifts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/fun-summer-gifts/">&lt;p&gt;We love summer. Do you love summer? We’ve been chatting up our friends and scrolling through Instagram, of course, to find a few fun summer gifts. Give them to yourself or someone else for whatever occasion inspires you this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-short-summer-gift-idea-list&quot;&gt;Our short summer gift idea list&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t even have to buy all of this cool stuff. We don’t link to shops or specific items because we think you can handle that part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-homemade-popsicles&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Homemade popsicles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously - the probability that someone will turn down a homemade popsicle is approximately &amp;lt; 1%. That’s a totally scientific number that we made up, but we are pretty sure it is true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make popsicles your own by following one of these three approaches to make the stuff to pour into your popsicle molds, or Dixie cups if you are really fancy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend milk and fruit - we use coconut milk and/or heavy cream to get extra fun creaminess&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make pudding - people love pudding pops - by people, we mostly mean kids&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go with straight juice - these are super sweet - we cut ours with water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-shell-or-rock-art&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Shell or rock art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom make a thing with some items you collect while out exploring (note, the real gift here is that you get to go exploring to get the things! - we are so sneaky).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect small shells or rocks at the beach - not if you are in a leave no trace kinda place - and glue or paint them to make a friend’s name or a frame for a picture of you together. It will hold up for years as a memory of your experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-yard-games&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Yard games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are partial to cornhole and horseshoes because they don’t take a great amount of effort and are portable. Go ahead and gift yourself a yard game and then invite everyone over to play…again and again. It is joy on repeat to gather friends and family together. Serve up some of those popsicles!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-custom-insulated-drinkware&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Custom insulated drinkware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know how you want your iced drinks, well, iced? Your friends and family do, too! You can be the person who sets everyone up with insulated drinkware with a favorite saying, joke, image, or just a name. We know there are so many makers who do this sort of thing; you can probably find one in your neighborhood. Celebrate the gift of cold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-waterproof-fold-or-roll-up-mats&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Waterproof fold or roll up mats&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be ready for an impromptu picnic, time at the beach, or a nap in the woods with a mat that will shield you from damp ground, bugs, and/or spiky plant parts. These mats roll or fold up, so you can just keep one in your car or go bag and bust it out in a time of need. Any time can be outside time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope you have a splendid summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/815996026210435288/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><category term="ideas" /><summary type="html">We love summer. Do you love summer? We’ve been chatting up our friends and scrolling through Instagram, of course, to find a few fun summer gifts. Give them to yourself or someone else for whatever occasion inspires you this summer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">July Instagram Challenge</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/july-ig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="July Instagram Challenge" /><published>2018-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/july-ig</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/july-ig/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Summer is a state of mind”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our heart and soul is in our wonderful suppliers, and we want everyone to have a little fun this summer. To that end, we are continuing our instagram challenge for suppliers, and anyone can join the fun. Let’s see what direction your month takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;July Gifts Done Instagram Challenge&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.gifts-done.com/assets/images/ig_challenge_july.png&quot; alt=&quot;gifts done instagram challenge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-the-most-of-it&quot;&gt;Make the Most of It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become part of the party by posting something related to the challenge each day. Be sure to also use and follow the main challenge hashtag &lt;strong&gt;#gdempowers&lt;/strong&gt; - this is how everyone can see your posts and we can repost you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is so exciting to see how other people use a prompt. Be wild, be wacky, just be yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate other makers and creators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet new people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-repost-you&quot;&gt;We’ll Repost You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love seeing what our suppliers (and future suppliers) are up to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="social" /><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html">“Summer is a state of mind”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">22 Self Care Ideas</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/22selfcare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="22 Self Care Ideas" /><published>2018-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/22selfcare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/22selfcare/">&lt;p&gt;How are you feeling?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel tense, overwhelmed, nervous, or uncomfortable, it may be time to take a self-care break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because we love you, we spent a few minutes coming up with a list of 22 ideas for self care. You can try these as written or build on them to come up with something that is just right for you. Don’t let our ideas hold back your creativity and expression!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;Peaceful rock stacking&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.gifts-done.com/assets/images/jeremy-thomas-75753-unsplash&quot; alt=&quot;stacked pebbles Photo by Jeremy Thomas on Unsplash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sit in the sunshine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get out pencil and paper and draw a baby elephant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dig a hole&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build a spaceship out of toy bricks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find some crayons and melt them together to make a giant crayon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solve a rubix cube (&lt;em&gt;working: not if this will make you angry&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draw your name in bubble letters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get dressed up in a way that makes you feel fabulous and get a friend to take your picture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read a YA novel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put your headphones in, put your current favorite song on repeat and sing along&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List out all of the things that you are thinking about&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clip your nails&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take your dog, or a shelter dog, for a walk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cover your whole body with moisturizer after bathing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to the beach or woods, try to find two things that are the same&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a blanket fort, take a snack, flashlight, and magazine inside&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plant something&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do a jigsaw puzzle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blow bubbles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a kids coloring book - color an easy picture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Splash in the rain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Draw a maze and then solve it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A little tip - research shows that little doses of self care are critical to mental health and wellness. Constantly feeding ourselves with treats and rewards can be hazardous to that same mental health. Please self-care responsibly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="selfcare" /><summary type="html">How are you feeling?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">June Instagram Challenge</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/june-ig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="June Instagram Challenge" /><published>2018-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/june-ig</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/june-ig/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life is short - smile while you still have teeth.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our heart and soul is in our wonderful suppliers, and we want everyone to have a little fun. To that end, we created an instagram challenge for suppliers, but anyone can join the fun. Let’s see what direction your month takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;June Gifts Done Instagram Challenge&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.gifts-done.com/assets/images/ig_challenge_june.png&quot; alt=&quot;gifts done instagram challenge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-the-most-of-it&quot;&gt;Make the Most of It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become part of the party by posting something related to the challenge each day. Be sure to also use and follow the main challenge hashtag &lt;strong&gt;#gdempowers&lt;/strong&gt; - this is how everyone can see your posts and we can repost you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is so exciting to see how other people use a prompt. Be wild, be wacky, just be yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate other makers and creators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet new people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-repost-you&quot;&gt;We’ll Repost You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love seeing what our suppliers (and future suppliers) are up to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="social" /><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html">“Life is short - smile while you still have teeth.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Apologize for a Missed Gift</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/apologize/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Apologize for a Missed Gift" /><published>2018-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/apologize</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/apologize/">&lt;p&gt;Many of our customers at Gifts Done are just like us (shocker) and have missed gifts in the past. In fact, most of the feedback that we get from users is how they love not doing that anymore because we take care of them. If you are not using an automated gifting service, it is possible, maybe, that you will miss an important day for someone. It feels terrible, right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1499171138085-a60c4e752ff7?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=a0423a28d0490b60b12192def27aa4c4&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1050&amp;amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;sadman&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mistakes happen - and it can make you feel terrible&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are all different, of course, and you may have friends and family who don’t care about their birthdays and anniversaries and what not. However, when you do forget for someone who is close to you, there can be hurt feelings. Both for them and you. There’s no need to beat yourself up about it - you can simply not go back into the past and change your actions. You can take control and recover. Here’s our 3 step plan - don’t be shocked at how simple it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-acknowledge-that-you-made-a-mistake&quot;&gt;1. Acknowledge that you made a mistake&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more for you than anyone else. Start here. If you are not ready to talk to the person who you have hurt, start with you. “I have made a mistake”. Then, you start to own the process of recovery and you can address what has happened. Mistakes happen, so this step puts the missed gift into a category of things we know how to handle. At this point, you don’t want to make any promises to yourself or anyone else. You want to figure out the root cause. Here are possible mistakes that some people make that cause them to miss important days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You did not know when or what the event was&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You did not know that the person cared so much&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You were aware of the upcoming event but you did not make a plan to do anything about it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You were aware of the upcoming event and you made a plan but you did not stick with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these are possible - there may even be more. The point here is just to find out where the gap is that let you make a mistake. You can be really specific if you want or just think about it in general terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-determine-a-strategy-for-not-repeating-the-mistake&quot;&gt;2. Determine a strategy for not repeating the mistake&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Once you know why you missed this special day, it is much easier to figure out how to do something about it.&lt;/em&gt; Not all causes can have a clear plan of action, though. If you just didn’t know, it is fine, but not really actionable, to say, “I won’t let this happen again because I will pay more attention/ask more/know more in the future” Frankly, we just don’t know what we don’t know, and there is nothing that can be done about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our experience - most missed gifts are caused by people just not being able to get to gifts because there are so many other competing priorities - people are trying to give 100% of themselves to work, family, hobbies, etc. When you have so many truly important things to do, it can be hard to remember much less prioritize shopping or sometimes even just saying “I am so happy for you on this day” - because the actual day slips our minds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your strategies may vary, but here are a few that we’ve used or heard others using:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monthly planning&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain a habit of actively searching for, listing, and taking action on important events every month - one of our users even suggested putting sticky notes by the door with each date - so you may have one that says “May 20 - Sally’s 40th birthday” that you stick up there on May 1 and have to walk past and look at every day. It sounds kind of genius, really.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set up a reminder service&lt;/strong&gt; There are plenty of reminder services where you can enter dates and get a phone call or text message to do something. One way to customize your reminders is through the If This Than That application - so you can get just the right kind of notification for you - you can even connect the reminder to your smart lights now, so maybe you want the lights to be purple when there is something you need to do. We don’t know what will work best for your situation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use a service like Gifts Done&lt;/strong&gt; Obviously, we are a little biased here. Setting up all of your gift events with your own budget and notes just when it works for you, is the easiest way. You can even get an annual membership so that you can save money when you send more than 10 gifts per year. It is easy and you know that your gifts will come from and benefit small businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask people to remind you&lt;/strong&gt; It seems a little weird, but you can ask people to let you know when things that are important to them are coming up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1484973768669-7fb6b5451095?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=b5cc69681633be6abd6a87cd8d3b350e&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1049&amp;amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;women on couch head down&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;A genuine apology is tough but oh so quick&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-genuinely-apologize&quot;&gt;3. Genuinely apologize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are empowered with understanding how you made a mistake and what you can do about it to avoid it next time - now it is time to apologize. We recommend doing this in person (if possible) and one on one. Apologies can feel hard at first, and you may be nervous. You can psych yourself up by thinking about how you feel when someone apologizes to you. You probably don’t bite, and they probably won’t either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always start with a simple, “I’m sorry” and never use the word “but”.&lt;/em&gt; Apologies are almost always of the formula: simple sorry + what I did + how I will do better next time. They do not include excuses or turn the attention back on the apologizer. This is important. If you made a mistake, even if the other person made one too, you can only own your own mistake. If Sally never told me that her birthday is May 20, and I miss it - well, I did not know that it was her birthday and the root cause of that could be that she did not tell me. I can still make her feel better by saying something like, “I am sorry that I missed your birthday. I did not know it was your birthday, and I have it in my calendar now, so we can celebrate next year!”. Now, everyone feels better. If Sally chooses to apologize to me for unreasonable expectations - that is a completely different matter than I have no control over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s wishing you never need apologize.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/815996026210434224/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="questions" /><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">Many of our customers at Gifts Done are just like us (shocker) and have missed gifts in the past. In fact, most of the feedback that we get from users is how they love not doing that anymore because we take care of them. If you are not using an automated gifting service, it is possible, maybe, that you will miss an important day for someone. It feels terrible, right!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3 Rules to Regift with Confidence</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/regift/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Rules to Regift with Confidence" /><published>2018-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/regift</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/regift/">&lt;p&gt;Worried about regifting? Never fear, there are rules for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“My friend gave me this beautiful vase, but it has been in my cupboard for a year, and I know another friend would actual use it. Is it okay to regift.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I just received two different desk sets when I started a new job, and I can only use one. How do I use one and not hurt my other friend.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions like these come up all of the time. While you may not have a beautiful gifted vase or two desk sets weighing you down, you may have faced a similar dilemma. The real issue is made more complicated by our competing wants. &lt;em&gt;We want to not waste things AND we want to let people know we appreciate the gifts they give to us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing when and how to regift is more of an art than a science (or else, we would all just know what to do). Thankfully, there are rules that reduce the risk that your regifting will be either wasteful or hurtful. Follow these three rules and regift with confidence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-never-regift-to-the-gifter&quot;&gt;1. Never Regift to the Gifter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem obvious, but it is the most common rule broken in regifting. Why might that be so? Because we usually give people things that we find valuable or pleasing in some way. So, your friend Mary, who loves purple, may give you a purple kitten scarf because SHE thinks it is snappy and fun and look fabulous on you. If you look at it a few months later, you may think, &lt;em&gt;“hmmm, Mary would l-o-o-o-v-e that purple scarf, and I never wear it.”&lt;/em&gt; There are two ways to prevent this foible, one good, one less good. The first one we already wrote about - &lt;a href=&quot;/keep-gift-log/&quot;&gt;keep a log of what you get from everyone&lt;/a&gt;, and it is the best way to avoid regifting the gifter. The less good way is to work the gift item up into conversation and try to find out if they gave it to you. It is less good because it is hard to navigate this conversational mess and then turn around and give someone something. However, having an awkward conversation is still better than regifting to the gifter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-give-with-honesty&quot;&gt;2. Give with Honesty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are regifting, do not try to pretend that you have recently made or purchased the gift. You may not be caught in your lie, but it gains you nothing and risks the trust of your relationship. If the item has a tag, you can leave it on or remove it, depending on your preferences and how you are packaging. Being honest does not mean being annoyingly honest - You don’t have to come right out and say, “I got this thing and really don’t like it.” Feel confident enough to own the regift if your giftee recognizes the item or asks you directly. People appreciate honesty more than stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-be-thoughtful&quot;&gt;3. Be Thoughtful&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regifting is no different than gifting in this regard. You want to be thoughtful when gifting. Stop and think about the whole person before giving a gift - a poorly timed, presented, or considered gift can be worse than no gift at all. Being thoughtful does not mean that you will always get it right - you are not a mind reader and people are fallible. It is okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.pexels.com/photos/264791/pexels-photo-264791.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;amp;h=350&quot; alt=&quot;just for you boxes&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;Thoughtful regifting can feel like it was just for you to begin with!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a good regifting story? We’d love to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="questions" /><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">Worried about regifting? Never fear, there are rules for this.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">May Instagram Challenge</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/may-ig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="May Instagram Challenge" /><published>2018-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/may-ig</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/may-ig/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You have brains in your head. You have feet in your shoes. You can steer yourself, any direction you choose.”
― Dr. Seuss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our heart and soul is in our wonderful suppliers, and we want everyone to have a little fun. To that end, we created an instagram challenge for suppliers, but anyone can join the fun. Let’s see what direction your May takes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;May Gifts Done Instagram Challenge&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://blog.gifts-done.com/assets/images/ig_challenge_may.png&quot; alt=&quot;gifts done instagram challenge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-the-most-of-it&quot;&gt;Make the Most of It&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become part of the party by posting something related to the challenge each day. Be sure to also use and follow the main challenge hashtag &lt;strong&gt;#gdempowers&lt;/strong&gt; - this is how everyone can see your posts and we can repost you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is so exciting to see how other people use a prompt. Be wild, be wacky, just be yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Celebrate other makers and creators&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet new people!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;well-repost-you&quot;&gt;We’ll Repost You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love seeing what our suppliers (and future suppliers) are up to.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="social" /><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html">“You have brains in your head. You have feet in your shoes. You can steer yourself, any direction you choose.” ― Dr. Seuss</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Keep a Gift Log</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/keep-gift-log/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep a Gift Log" /><published>2018-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/keep-gift-log</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/keep-gift-log/">&lt;p&gt;Logging all of the things - it really helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, I found a “Little Irish Birthday Book” on the clearance rack of the bookstore. The book was simply a list of every day that occurs in a year, so you can write a name. With this little book, my gift logging was born. I started entering in every person who I met. When I gave a gift, I would add an entry under their name with the year and what I sent and a smiley face if they liked it - &lt;em&gt;I did not realize I was ahead of my time with the whole emoji thing&lt;/em&gt;. I found out that it could only hold a few years of information and it had no good place for me to track what I was receiving, which I started to be curious about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the proliferation of smart things - phones, watches, lights, etc., we are logging more and more of our lives. If you keep up with bullet journalling, you may notice that people also track moods, sleep, instagram posts, and more. Applying the tried and true method of logging to gifting will, wait for it, change your life. I’m not kidding - rather than bore you with a litany of reasons why you should be logging your gifting, I’ll keep it to &lt;strong&gt;3 reasons you should be keeping a gift log&lt;/strong&gt; and then a quick &lt;strong&gt;How to keep a gift log&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/815996026210421813/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-reasons-you-should-be-keeping-a-gift-log&quot;&gt;Three reasons you should be keeping a gift log&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-magnify-gratitude&quot;&gt;1. Magnify Gratitude&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping a log of things helps us not only to remember the past but also to be more aware of the present. I put this first because it is so powerful. It only takes a second to write down a description of what someone gave to you, just flip through your log (if you are keeping one) or put it in your journal. Research shows that we will be even more thankful if we write down specific things about the gift that we like - so, go crazy with the details!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-know-what-they-like&quot;&gt;2. Know What They Like&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once, I gave a friend a funny joke mug that I thought she would like, but it turned out that she had a full set of pottery made by her grandfather and simply did not use any other dishes. That’s the kind of thing that you learn over time. I made a note in my book never to do it again. Another time, I found out about a baby shower a little late and ended up arriving only with some fancy chocolates for the Mom. She loved them so much that I gave her the same chocolates in different settings for the few years we lived close. Keeping track of what people do and do not respond to is helpful for you to make people happy. Also - making people happy makes us happy - it’s like a happy bouncy thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-never-repeat-a-gift&quot;&gt;3. Never Repeat a Gift&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever gotten the exact same set of cat stickers from someone two gifts in a row? No? Well, I have. It is weird because clearly you like cat stickers, &lt;em&gt;who doesn’t&lt;/em&gt; but maybe you didn’t use up the last roll yet! Don’t be that person. When you track what you gift someone, it is so easy to avoid this because you can see everything that you have ever gifted them. Some gifts are great for repeats, like coffee dates or movie tickets, but physical items are mostly good for one go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-keep-a-gift-log&quot;&gt;How to Keep a Gift Log&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can keep your gift log anywhere. I recommend a dedicated notebook. It can be a physical notebook or a digital one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s one way to set up your gift log notebook. First, count the number of pages and divide the total by 12, and the result is the number of pages per month (120 pages means 10 pages per month). You can write little page numbers in the bottom if you want to have an index, but then you need to subtract one from the total because it will be the index :stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:. I’d put a little labeled tab and the name of the month on the first page. I’d like to pretend it is all artsy, but I use block letters. After you label each month, you have 9 pages to work with. For most months, this will last years and years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You just put in the person’s name and their birthdate, like “Amy (7/30)”. This starts Amy’s block. Generally, I put one person on a page to start a month. &lt;em&gt;If you have more than nine people you are giving gifts to, good for you!&lt;/em&gt; Under each name, just add a year and a description. In my example, Amy and I are just exchanging birthday gifts, but you can add little tags, like “Christmas” or “Nurses Day” to keep a more complicated log.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/example-giftlog-amy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Log Example&quot; /&gt;

  &lt;figcaption&gt;An Example Gift Log from my book...I need to get some more of those melty mints!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d love to see your journal. We follow #bettergifting on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/gifts_done/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; for things like this, or send us an email.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">Logging all of the things - it really helps.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 No Cost Ways to Spread Joy</title><link href="http://blog.gifts-done.com/5ways-nocost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 No Cost Ways to Spread Joy" /><published>2018-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://blog.gifts-done.com/5ways-nocost</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://blog.gifts-done.com/5ways-nocost/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’ve learned that people will forget what you said, people will forget what you did, but people will never forget how you made them feel.”
― Maya Angelou&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think that a lot is communicated in how people feel, and &lt;strong&gt;we want people to feel joy&lt;/strong&gt;.  That’s not just a gimmick. We believe in self-care, family-care, friend-care. Here are 5 no cost ways to show people that you care and spread joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-invite-them-to-go-for-a-walk-with-you&quot;&gt;1. Invite them to go for a walk with you&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;by Jonas Weckschmied, Unsplash&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1469989336803-8876b8443f06?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=40c67e788265b1f0dce05673e6bccfbc&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=400&amp;amp;q=60&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;
An invitation is a beautiful thing, regardless of its form. We feel included and may even do things that we want to do but avoid because of lack of motivation. Inviting a friend to walk with you may give them just enough reason to get up and do something they wanted to do anyways! In addition, walking with other people - socially - has been shown to reduce depression.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We all know that there are physical benefits as well, so go out and walk. Chat them up during the walk. It will do you both some good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-make-them-a-meal-or-treat&quot;&gt;2. Make them a meal or treat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;by Nordwood Themes, Unsplash&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1488045212212-a5b5b0f8d3fc?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=fc70649381f3806d32aa42a4fef3e009&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=180&amp;amp;q=60&quot; alt=&quot;cupcakes&quot; /&gt;
They say that the way to a man’s heart is through his stomach, but it is true for ladies and kids as well. Have you ever offered a cookie to someone and not made an instant friend? Don’t worry about appearance or amount, either. Real people know that it doesn’t matter to taste. It’s enough that you care. Secret tip - you can make yourself or your family a treat or meal and just increase the portions a little or double to share with someone else. Luckily, cooking for others benefits us, too. Studies show that people who are cooking or making things for others feel more confidence, feel happier, and feel stronger connections to the people who they are cooking for.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-create-something-for-them&quot;&gt;3. Create something for them&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;by rawpixel.com, Unsplash&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1521623569012-4eb30b21369a?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=28ee2f63a210ba9ebacd002c1f7dbf8c&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=330&amp;amp;q=60&quot; alt=&quot;pencil ready&quot; /&gt;
You have talents that you may not yet know of. Try to draw a little doodle, write a poem, paint a tiny canvas, or make an origami frog. There are so many little creative possibilities. The thing is, it doesn’t have to be perfect. Your fingerprint ladybug may just crack them up in the moment - it may never end up in a museum, or even a permanent place on your friend’s wall or fridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-give-them-a-call&quot;&gt;4. Give them a call&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;by rawpixel.com, Unsplash&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; style=&quot;padding:5px;&quot; src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1519781916412-663d649a4359?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=d92c5bbab6ff94740dc373fda5bae067&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=270&amp;amp;q=60&quot; alt=&quot;man on phone&quot; /&gt; When was the last time that you called someone or received a call - not for scheduling a dentist appointment or something but to chat? It seems like a rare treat these days. Even if they cannot talk to you, hearing your voice fumbling through the voicemail or seeing a missed call can help someone feel loved. It is so easy. If you don’t have much time, that is fine - just politely hang up after a short discussion. Not sure how to start talking to someone after it has been awhile. Prepare ahead of time with a question or an invitation - do they know something that you could ask them about or could you get together in person?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-pay-them-a-real-complement&quot;&gt;5. Pay them a real complement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an every day option - you can give these out all the time. Strangers, friends, family - it does not matter. …but there is a reason that complement is qualified with ‘real’. People can usually tell when we are being, er, frivolous with our complements. Genuine appreciation of something that he or she did is so much more meaningful than calling out immutable things like appearance. Here are a few examples, “Wow, you have a way with words - I’d never have thought of, ‘witty-thing-they-said’“… “These ‘insert food/art product’ are divine. I am impressed with your ‘insert specific something’”. Secret tip - Practice with strangers if you are afraid of sounding like a robot around your friends!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great perk of all of these - science shows that giving benefits us even without expectation of getting something back. So, every effort to give someone else joy brings it back to you!&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-pin-do=&quot;embedPin&quot; data-pin-terse=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/pin/815996026210422229/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Hanson S, Jones A. Is there evidence that walking groups have health benefits? A systematic review and meta-analysis Br J Sports Med 2015;49:710-715. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Thomson, Julie R. The Very Real Psychological Benefits Of Cooking For Other People. Huffington Post. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/benefits-of-cooking-for-others_us_5967858ae4b0a0c6f1e67a15&quot;&gt;full text&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Konnikova, Maria. The Psychology Behind Gift-Giving and Generosity. Scientific American 2012; January 4. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.scientificamerican.com/literally-psyched/the-psychology-behind-gift-giving-and-generosity/&quot;&gt;full text&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Gifts Done</name><email>hello@gifts-done.com</email></author><category term="gifts" /><summary type="html">“I’ve learned that people will forget what you said, people will forget what you did, but people will never forget how you made them feel.” ― Maya Angelou</summary></entry></feed>